Guide to the James Beard Papers ca. 1950-1980 MSS 263
© 2010 Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series II: Assorted Writing
  - Subseries A: Articles, etc.
    - "Bourbon: America's Own," Home and Garden, January 1960 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Breakfast, undated (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Broiling and Grilling, undated (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Broths, undated (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Casseroles, Cassoulets and Other Oven Delights, undated (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Cassoulet, undated (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Cold Foods, undated (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Curing Pork, undated (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Dandelions, undated (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Duck, undated (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Fish Fillet Cookbook, [House and Garden], undated (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Grill Ideas, undated (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - I Dig Clams, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - [Irma Rombauer], undated (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - James Beard on American Food, undated (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - The Kitchen: Where the Heart Lies, undated (Box 8, Folder 37)
    - The Knives in Your Life, undated (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - Know Your Meat Cut, undated (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - Macaroni, undated (Box 8, Folder 40)
    - Maryland Talk, undated (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - Mayonaise, undated (Box 8, Folder 42)
    - New York Times Article, undated (Box 8, Folder 43)
    - Notes for Esquire Article, undated (Box 8, Folder 44)
    - The Quiche Cookbook, undated (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - Piemonte (Piedmont), undated (Box 8, Folder 46)
    - Beard/Wilson, SoHo News Column, undated (Box 8, Folder 47)
    - Spring and Summer Vegetables, undated (Box 8, Folder 48)
    - Thanksgiving, undated (Box 8, Folder 49)
    - III, undated (Box 8, Folder 50)
    - Tour d'Argent, undated (Box 8, Folder 51)
    - [Travel Writing], undated (Box 8, Folder 52)
    - Turkey, undated (Box 8, Folder 53)
    - [Various], undated (Box 8, Folder 54)
    - Veal, undated (Box 8, Folder 55)
    - Venison, undated (Box 8, Folder 56)
    - Wine and Food, undated (Box 8, Folder 57)
  - Subseries B: Notes
    - How to Eat (and Drink) Your Way through a French (and Italian) Menu, acknowledgement notes, undated (Box 8, Folder 58)
    - Notebook, undated (Box 8, Folder 59)
    - Notepad, undated (Box 8, Folder 60)
    - Notepad, undated (Box 8, Folder 61)
    - [Notes], undated (Box 8, Folder 62)
    - [Notes], undated (Box 8, Folder 63)
    - [Notes], undated (Box 8, Folder 64)
    - [Notes], undated (Box 8, Folder 65)
    - [Notes], undated (Box 8, Folder 66)
  - Subseries C: Works by Others with Comments by Beard
    - Brown/Peterson; FOW/The Cooking of the United States, Chapter II, first draft [annotated], undated (Box 8, Folder 67)
    - Harlech, Pamela, Feast without Fuss, undated (Box 8, Folder 68)
    - Hom, Ken with Steiman, Harvey; Techniques of Chinese Cooking [draft], undated (Box 8, Folder 69)
    - Kump, Peter, About Quiche and Pate, rough draft [annotated], undated (Box 8, Folder 70)
    - The Portland Woman's Exchange Cook Book [annotated photocopies], undated (Box 8, Folder 71)
- Series III: Recurring Television Shows and Columns
  This series is comprised of recurring, non-manuscript writing, including scripts from television shows and various magazine columns. Subseries are arranged alphabetically by project title.
  - Subseries A: Beard on Food, 1969-1971
    - Beard on Food, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 72)
    - Beard on Food, 1969-70 (Box 8, Folder 73)
    - Beard on Food, January - June 1970 (Box 8, Folder 74)
    - Beard on Food, July - December 1970 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Beard on Food, January - June 1971 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Beard on Food, July - December 1971 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Beard on Food, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Beard on Food, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Notes, Beard on Food, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - [Reviews, Beard on Food], 1974 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Running Heads - Recipe and Column Titles, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Subseries B: Cook Along with James Beard, cassette series, undated
    - [Scripts], undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Tentative Menus, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Subseries C: Dollars and Sense Cooking, 1971-72 (Box [13])
    - [Scripts], January - April 1971 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - [Scripts], May - September 1971 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - [Scripts], October - November 1971 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - [Scripts], October - December 1971 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - [Scripts], January - February 1972 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - [Scripts], March - April 1972 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - [Scripts], May - September 1972 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - [Scripts], October - December 1972 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Subseries D: Gourmet Magazine
    - "Cooking With Jim Beard: Boiling and Poaching", January 1969 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - "Cooking with James Beard: Broiling and Grilling", February 1969 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - "Cooking with James Beard: Roasting - Lamb and Mutton", April 1969 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - "Cooking with James Beard: Roasting - Pork", May 1969 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - "Cooking with James Beard: Roasting - Chicken and Turkey", June 1969 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - "Cooking with James Beard: Game Birds", September 1969 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - "Cooking with James Beard: Furred Game", October 1969 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - "Cooking with James Beard: Desserts for Christmas", November 1969 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - "Cooking with James Beard: French Christmas Food", December 1969 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - "Cooking with James Beard: Braising - Beef", January 1970 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - "Cooking with James Beard: Braising - Lamb", February 1970 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - "Cooking with James Beard: Braising - Veal", March 1970 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - "Cooking with James Beard: Fish - Poaching", April 1970 (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - "Cooking with James Beard: Composed Salads", August 1970 (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - "Cooking with James Beard: Fruit", July 1971 (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - "Cooking with James Beard: Grill Accompaniments", August 1971 (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - "Cooking with James Beard: Frozen Desserts", December 1971 (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - "Cooking with James Beard: Tea and Crumpets...", April 1972 (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - "Cooking with James Beard: Rice", December 1972 (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - "Cooking with James Beard: Rice" [annotated photocopy], December 1972 (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - "Cooking with James Beard: Bombs and Other Frozen Desserts", undated (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Cooking with James Beard: Braised Veal", undated (Box 10, Folder 40)
    - "Cooking with James Beard: Braising Beef", undated (Box 10, Folder 41)
    - "Cooking with James Beard: Ham", undated (Box 10, Folder 42)
    - "Cooking with James Beard: Homemade Ice Cream", undated (Box 10, Folder 43)
    - "Cooking with James Beard: Luncheon Specialties", undated (Box 10, Folder 44)
    - Assorted Pages from James Beard Articles in Gourmet, undated (Box 10, Folder 45)
    - [Gourmet Notes], undated (Box 10, Folder 46)
  - Subseries E: James Beard's Kitchen
    - [Scripts], 1981 (Box 10, Folder 47)
  - Subseries F: Woman's Day
    - Articles and Correspondence, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 48)
    - "Christmas", undated (Box 10, Folder 49)
    - "Christmas" [annotated], undated (Box 10, Folder 50)
    - Introduction to Casseroles and Cassoulets, undated (Box 10, Folder 51)
    - "Spices and Herbs", undated (Box 10, Folder 52)
    - "Thanksgiving Story", undated (Box 10, Folder 53)
    - [Various], undated (Box 10, Folder 54)
    - [Woman's Day Proofs of Beard Articles], 1959-60 (Box 10, Folder 55)
    - [Woman's Day Proofs of Beard Articles], 1972-73 (Box 10, Folder 56)
- Series IV: Correspondence (Box [4-5])
  This series contains Beard's professional and personal correspondence. All materials in original folders were kept together with the original folder titles. Loose correspondence that did not appear to be in any particular order was arranged chronologically.
  - [Correspondence], 1953 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - [Correspondence], 1954 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - [Correspondence], 1955 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - [Correspondence], 1956 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - [Correspondence], 1957 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - [Correspondence], 1958 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - [Correspondence], 1959 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - [Correspondence], 1960 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - [Correspondence], 1961 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - [Correspondence], 1962 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - [Correspondence], 1963 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - [Correspondence], 1964 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - [Correspondence], 1965 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - [Correspondence], 1966 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - [Correspondence], 1967 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - [Correspondence], 1968 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - [Correspondence], 1969 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - [Correspondence], 1970 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - [Correspondence], 1971 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - [Correspondence], 1972 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - [Correspondence], 1972 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - [Correspondence], 1973 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - [Correspondence], 1973 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - [Correspondence], 1974 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - [Correspondence], 1974 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - [Correspondence], 1975 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - [Correspondence], 1975 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - [Correspondence], 1976 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - [Correspondence], 1976 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - [Correspondence], 1977 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - [Correspondence], 1977 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - [Correspondence], 1977 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - [Correspondence], 1978 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - [Correspondence], 1978 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - [Correspondence], 1979 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - [Correspondence], 1980 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - [Correspondence], 1981 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - [Correspondence], 1982 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - [Correspondence], undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - [Correspondence], undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence - Helen Evans Brown, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence - The University of Wyoming, 1973-76 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - [Invitations], 1973-82 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - [Invitations], undated (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - [Mailing Labels to The University of Wyoming], undated (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1973-74 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Send to Wyoming [1 of 2], 1980 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Send to Wyoming [2 of 2], 1979- 80 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Wyoming, 1979-80 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Wyoming, undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Series V: Personal, 1950s-1980s
  This series contains Beard's personal materials, including awards, calendars, certificates, datebooks, itineraries and receipts. Materials are arranged alphabetically within two subseries: General and Awards.
  - Subseries A: General
    - Address Book, undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Airline Tickets, 1969-73 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Business Cards, 1967-8 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Business Cards (not Beard's), undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Calendars, 1965-1973 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Certificate, Who's Who in America, 1978/1979 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Cookbook Catalog [annotated notecards] (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Datebook, 1953 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Datebook, 1954 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Datebook, 1955 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Datebook, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Datebook, 1957 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Datebook, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Datebook, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Datebook, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Datebook, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Datebook, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Datebook, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Datebook, 1966 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Datebook, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Employer's Quarterly Federal Tax Return, September 1962 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Exhibitor Badge, National Housewares Exposition, James Beard, Corning Glass Works, July 1974 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Financial Statements, 1950s-70s (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Founding Member Certificate, The Blair House Library Foundation, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Glasses (Box 22)
    - Guest Badge, 1973 Western Governors' Conference, James Andrew Beard (Box 22)
    - Honorable Discharge Certificate, 1943 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Income from column articles demos..., 1978-79 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Instructions Re: Federal Income Tax Return, 1952 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Itinerary, February 20, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Itinerary, Europe, 1966 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Itinerary, The Export Council of Norway, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Itinerary, Paul and Julia Child, [1971] (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Itinerary for Cleo and Lester Gruber and James A. Beard, 1966 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Medical Records, 1970-1 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Membership Cards, 1973-74 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Name Tag, Corning: James Beard, undated (Box 22)
    - Paid checks, 1962 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Passports, 1953-61 (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Pin, "Cooking in the 70s" (Box 22)
    - Plaque, Christmas Dinner, [December 25, 1967] (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Receipts, 1960-9 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Recipes Cards, A-B, undated (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Recipes Cards, C, undated (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Recipes Cards, D-G, undated (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Recipes Cards, H-M, undated (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - Recipes Cards, N-P, undated (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - Recipes Cards, Q-Si, undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Recipes Cards, So-end, undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Royalties, 1966-73 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Seaside 1975 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Stationery, undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Swatches, Bel y Cia, undated (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Washington High School, 60th Anniversary Celebration, February 22, 1966 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Washington Star Syndicate, Inc., sales for Jan. 29 to Feb. 25, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Wooden box, undated (Box 22)
    - Yellow Scarf, undated (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Subseries B: Awards
    - Award Ribbon, "First", undated (Box 22)
    - Medal, Canadian Federation of Chefs de Cuisine, 1963 (Box 22)
    - Medal, Comite National Vins de France, undated (Box 22)
    - Medal and Ribbon, la Confrerie Americaine des Trinqueurs de Cognac, undated (Box 22)
    - Medal, Homenagem ao Grande Cidadao Brasileiro (Box 22)
    - Medal, Hommage a Son Fondateur Joseph Capus, Institut National des Appellations d'Origine des Vins et Eaux-de-Vie, 1956 (Box 22)
    - Medal, Internationale Kochkunst Ausstelluno, September 30-October 7, 1956 (Box 22)
    - Medal, Societe de Sonde 'a Fromage, undated (Box 22)
    - Ronald C. Schmitz Silver Spoon Award, National Association for the Specialty Food Trade, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 5)
      General note
      Originally attached to a blank block of wood.
- Series VI: Recipes
  This series contains the considerable array of foldered and loose recipes found among Beard's Papers. Foldered records were kept in their original order and for loose recipes, original order was maintained as much as possible by leaving groups of similarly focused recipes together, marked by the sqaure brackets surrounding their folder title. Loose recipes that did not appear to be in any particular order were placed in folders titled [Misc. Recipes].
  - Additional Basic Recipes, undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Additional Fish Recipes, undated (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Appetizers and First Courses, undated (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Armagnac, undated (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Assorted Recipes, undated (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - [Beans], undated (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - [Beef], undated (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Breads and Cookies, undated (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - [Bread and Pastry], undated (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - [Cake], undated (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Charcoal Grilled Vegetables, undated (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - [Cheese], undated (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - [Chicken], undated (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Christmas Cake Recipe, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - [Cognac], undated (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - [Custard and Pudding], undated (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Desserts, undated (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Desserts, undated (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Diet and 1/2 hr. meals, undated (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - le Diplomate des Isles, Simone Beck, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - [Duck], undated (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - [Eggs], undated (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Eggs, Cheese, Soufflets,etc., undated (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - [Fall], undated (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - Fish and Shellfish, undated (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - [Frosting and Dessert Sauce Recipes], undated (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - [Game Bird Recipes], undated (Box 15, Folder 34)
  - Grilled Fish, undated (Box 15, Folder 35)
  - Holiday Meals, undated (Box 15, Folder 36)
  - [Ice Cream and Sorbet Recipes], undated (Box 15, Folder 37)
  - Ices and Frozen Desserts, undated (Box 15, Folder 38)
  - Lamb Recipes, undated (Box 15, Folder 39)
  - Meat, undated (Box 15, Folder 40)
  - Meat, undated (Box 15, Folder 41)
  - [Meat], undated (Box 15, Folder 42)
  - Meat - General, Mixed, undated (Box 15, Folder 43)
  - Meat - Lamb, undated (Box 15, Folder 44)
  - [Meat Pie Recipes], undated (Box 15, Folder 45)
  - [Misc. Recipes], undated (Box 15, Folder 46)
  - [Misc. Recipes] (Box 15, Folder 47)
  - [Misc. Recipes] (Box 15, Folder 48)
  - [Misc. Recipes], undated (Box 15, Folder 49)
  - [Misc. Recipes], undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - [Misc. Recipes], undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - [Misc. Recipes], undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - [Misc. Recipes], undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - [Misc. Recipes], undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - [Misc. Recipes], undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - [Misc. Recipes], undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Offal (50 recipes), undated (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Pasta, Rice, Grain, Baked Dishes, undated (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Pasta, Rice, Grains, Gnoccchi, etc., undated (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Pastry, undated (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - [Picincs], undated (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - [Pie and Pie Crust Recipes], undated (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Poaching - Fish and Shellfish, undated (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Pop Corn Recipes [not Beard's], undated (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - [Pork Recipes], undated (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - [Pork Recipes], undated (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - [Potatoe Recipes], undated (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Poultry, undated (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - [Pudding Recipes], undated (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Quick Breads, undated (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - [Rabbit Recipes], undated (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Recipes: San Francisco Convention and Visitors Bureau, undated (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Recipes for Venice, undated (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Recipes from Other Sources, undated (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Results of Bread Tests, undated (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - [Rice Recipes], undated (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - [S&S], undated (Box 16, Folder 28)
  - [Salads and Dressings], undated (Box 16, Folder 29)
  - Salads and Herbs, undated (Box 16, Folder 30)
  - Salads and Misc., undated (Box 16, Folder 31)
  - Salmon and Sole, undated (Box 16, Folder 32)
  - [Sandwich Recipes], undated (Box 16, Folder 33)
  - [Sauce Recipes], undated (Box 16, Folder 34)
  - Simone Beck, undated (Box 16, Folder 35)
  - [Souffle Recipes], undated (Box 16, Folder 36)
  - [Soup Recipes], undated (Box 16, Folder 37)
  - Soups (extras), undated (Box 16, Folder 38)
  - Summer Punches, undated (Box 16, Folder 39)
  - Testing and Retesting, undated (Box 16, Folder 40)
  - Thanksgiving Menu, November 1969 (Box 16, Folder 41)
  - [Tripe Recipes], undated (Box 16, Folder 42)
  - [Turkey Recipes], undated (Box 16, Folder 43)
  - Various Recipes (1 of 3), undated (Box 16, Folder 44)
  - Various Recipes (2 of 3), undated (Box 16, Folder 45)
  - Various Recipes (3 of 3), undated (Box 16, Folder 46)
  - [Veal Recipes], undated (Box 16, Folder 47)
  - [Vegetable Recipes], undated (Box 16, Folder 48)
  - [Venison Recipes], undated (Box 16, Folder 49)
  - Wild Duck, undated (Box 16, Folder 50)
  - [Yafi], undated (Box 16, Folder 51)
- Series VII: Events
  This series contains materials regarding professional events Beard took part in, including cooking classes, contests and demonstrations. The materials are arranged alphabetically.
  - American Airways Lesson #4: Versatile Crepes (drafts), undated (Box 16, Folder 52)
  - American Airways Lesson #5, undated (Box 16, Folder 53)
  - American Cookery, Southwest, outline (revised), October 15, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 54)
  - American Meat Institute, Meat Information Conference, November 9, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 55)
  - American Meat Institute, Meat Information Conference, October 31, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 56)
  - Bloomingdales, "Cook's Kitchen", undated (Box 16, Folder 57)
  - Boscov's Famous Celebrities Gourmet Cooking School, undated (Box 16, Folder 58)
  - Bread World Presentation, September 18, 1968 (Box 16, Folder 59)
  - "Brockport Symphony proudly presents James Beard", [1977] (Box 16, Folder 60)
  - [Buffet at World Trade Center, diagram and notes], 1975-76 (Box 16, Folder 61)
  - Buffet Program, Layout, [Items], Proof, [1975-76] (Box 16, Folder 62)
  - Business Week Executive Chef Contest, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - "CBS Bicentennial Minutes", 1975 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - The Center Cirlce of the La Jolla Museum of Art welcomes you to "The Art of Cooking", October 12-14, [1966] (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Conversations about Food: James Beard, Cecilia Chiang, Jacques Pepin, postcard, undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - "Cooking with Style," A Filmstrip Scenario for E.I DuPont deNemours and Company, January 9, 1973 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Demonstration at J. Beard's 3/29/60, March 28, 1960 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - [Demonstration Menus], 1971 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Emporium Classes - Sept. 30-Oct. 2, 1981 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - "An Evening with Cognac Brandy" featuring James A. Beard, January 10, 1960 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Everson Museum Members Council and E.W. Edwards and Son present James A. Beard in Art and Artichokes, March 11-15, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - "First Performance" [annotated], undated (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Foretaste of Britain, press release, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - [Gourmet Courses at the Gritti Palace 1975], 1974-75 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Hightower presents James A. Beard in The Art of Cooking, II, November 6-11, 1967 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - J.B. and B.P.K. Notes, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - "James A. Beard and Phillip S. Brown Cooking Series", February 24-25, [1976] (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - The James A. Beard Cooking Classes - San Francisco, undated (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - James A. Beard Cooking Classes 1965 Royal Recipe Search Winners (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - "James Beard: Artist in the Kitchen with the Assistance of Carl Jerome", undated (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Kitchen Schedule for Testing and Photography, March 17, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Kraft Food Heritage Tour, 1973 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Lectures, 1960s-1970s (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Leisure Time and Food Report, undated (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Lessons I-VI, 1970-72 (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Lessons I-VI, undated (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - [Lesson Notes], undated (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Lessons: Simone Beck, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - List for Helen McCully Memorial Fund, undated (Box 17, Folder 28)
  - List for Registered Students for Fall Cooking Classes, undated (Box 17, Folder 29)
  - Materials from James Beard and Extracted Item Lists, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 30)
  - Memorandum, First Revision, February 18, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 31)
  - The Mid-Fairfield County Youth Museum presents James A. Beard and Ruth Norman in The Art of Cooking, March 1-5, 1965 (Box 17, Folder 32)
  - Monmouth College Demonstration, undated (Box 17, Folder 33)
  - The Museum of American Folk Art: Manhattan House Tour Benefit, November 4, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 34)
  - Name Lists, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 35)
  - Names for Waiting List, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 36)
  - Natural Gallery of Art, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 37)
  - [1977 Mushroom and Man Symposium], November 1977 (Box 17, Folder 38)
  - Omaha Steaks, undated (Box 17, Folder 39)